[Music]
English listening test part one designed
for A2
Learners this test consists of 20
questions which are divided into three
parts I will give you a short
instruction at the beginning of each
part before we get started take a pen
and paper so you can take notes while
listening are you ready let's get
started part one listen to five people
talking about their hobbies for each
person choose the two Hobbies they
mention my name is Emily I like to go to
the mountains with my friend John he
loves to walk but I can't do that
because of my bad knees so while he goes
hiking I paint I I took some lovely
pictures of a lake last month they are
on John's wall now I also love to watch
films I watch one every day yesterday I
saw one about some friends who started a
band they played their music around the
world and became famous it was
great I am Hannah I spend most of my
free time playing Island life it's a
computer game where you are on an island
and your mission is to survive you need
to grow plants for food and collect wood
in the forest so that you can cook and
build a home but when bad weather or
dangerous animals appear you can die and
then you have to start again it's cool I
also like to collect coins I have lots
of old coins some of them are rare I'm
always looking for more coins in shops
and on the
internet
I am James my friend Rob is a singer in
a band and last year he asked me to join
them because I play
drums so I did it and now we play
together it's fun we do a few shows
every week and we are sometimes on the
radio last week we played at a festival
in a beautiful garden with lots of
pretty flowers it was great my friends
in the band love partying and they often
go out after a show but I prefer to go
to bed with a good book I read two or
three every
week my name is
Simons my friend Robert grows vegetables
in his garden I'd like to do that too
but I live in a flat and don't have a
garden but I love going for long walks
in the
countryside I go for miles and miles and
I often come home with something like
mushrooms nuts or fruit then Robert and
I put everything in the kitchen and I
cooked dinner with it I love preparing
food in new ways maybe one day I will
invite some friends to a party and we'll
cook for
them I am Emma my neighbor plays in a
band and she practices her guitar every
evening loudly so I can't have a quiet
evening at home watching a film so I
often go out my friends are always
having parties and I go too I meet new
people and they invite me to more
parties it's fun and it's also a good
way to collect more cups I have about
300 now I like funny ones and ugly ones
it's fun to see the different cups in
people's kitchens you can learn about
people from their cups and sometimes
they give me one to take
home
[Music]
part two listen to a conversation
between a customer and a shop assistant
at a clothes shop and answer the
questions good morning how can I help
help
you hi I'm looking for a t-shirt for
spring of course we have a range over
here what size are
you can I try on a medium size in this
red
t-shirt certainly the fitting room is
just over
there it's too small do you have it in a
large let me check for you I'm afraid we
don't have a large in in red but we have
it in
white can I try the white one then
please
absolutely here you
are this one fits well I'll take this
one how much is it it's
$59.99 we offer a 10% discount if you
buy a second piece of
clothing that's nice I'll take a look at
those
jeans of course
I like the black Jean but I can't find
my size don't you have it in a
medium I'm afraid we don't we only have
a medium in blue or
white I'll try them
on
sure I like them both but I'll take the
blue one I wanted the white one but I've
already got a white
T-shirt yes how would you like to pay
can I pay in
cash of
course how much is it it's
$8.98 with the 10% discount that comes
to
$71 great here's
$150 thank you and here's $25 and change
your receipt and your
items thank you for shopping with
us thank you have have a great
[Music]
day
part three listen to three people
talking about what they are going to do
differently in the new year and answer
the
questions my name is
Jenny I put on weight last year when I
had my kids and I want to lose it but I
don't want to stop eating unhealthy
food I like cakes and chocolate too much
so I'm going to join a
gym it's expensive but if I pay for it I
will
go there are parent and baby swim
classes every morning and I want to go
to all of
those I hope I can meet people
there my name is Marcus last year I
decided to do more exercise so I started
cycling
but I fell off after 1 month and hurt my
back so I'm not going to do that again
but I want to lose weight so I'm going
to stop eating burgers and eat more
vegetables I'm also going to go swimming
at the sports center twice a week my
wife swims every day but I don't want to
do that because I want to work in the
garden too that will take a lot of time
and keep me fit I also want to spend
more time with my friends my kids are
older now so they don't need me at
home my name is Mike I got a new bike
for Christmas and I plan to use it I
want to go a 100 miles each week on it I
also want to join the photography
classes at the local College then I can
take some great pictures when I'm out on
my rides and I'm going to spend more
time with my kids last year I spent a
lot of of time driving to work so I
didn't see them in the mornings or
evenings but now I have a new job and I
work from home so I can be here for them
we can do fun things like making cakes
and playing in the garden it will be
fun
[Music]
don't forget to share your score in the
comments
section if you haven't taken our
previous listening tests the playlist
link is in the description
below we will upload more listening
tests so don't forget to subscribe and
stay tuned see you in our upcoming
videos